<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syntax Highlighting on Emacs Tree-sitter</title>
    <link>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Syntax Highlighting on Emacs Tree-sitter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Queries</title>
      <link>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/queries/</guid>
      <description>A query is a set of patterns, written in a Lisp-like syntax.
Queries are language-specific. Different language grammars use different node types and field names. Examples in this section apply to Rust.
 Patterns A pattern is an S-expression (Lisp form), optionally preceded by a field name, suffixed with a quantifier, and/or followed by a capture name.
A node form is a list form whose first element is a symbol (except for the special symbols, described later).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customization</title>
      <link>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/customization/</guid>
      <description>Faces tree-sitter-hl-mode provides a richer set of faces than font-lock-mode. For example, function definitions are highlighted with tree-sitter-hl-face:function, while function calls are highlighted with tree-sitter-hl-face:function.call. However, for compatibility with existing themes, the default values for most of these faces inherit from built-in font-lock faces.
If you want to leverage the full power of Tree-sitter&amp;rsquo;s syntax highlighting approach, you should customize these faces.
Capture Mappings By default, when the highlighting query associates a node with CAPTURE-NAME, it will be highlighted with the face tree-sitter-hl-face:CAPTURE-NAME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interface for Modes</title>
      <link>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/interface-for-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ubolonton.github.io/emacs-tree-sitter/syntax-highlighting/interface-for-modes/</guid>
      <description>Major modes that want to integrate with tree-sitter-hl-mode should set the variable tree-sitter-hl-default-patterns. It plays a similar role to font-lock-defaults.
Minor modes that want to customize syntax highlighting should call the function tree-sitter-hl-add-patterns.
The language-bundle package tree-sitter-langs provides highlighting queries for several languages. These queries will be used when the corresponding major modes do not set tree-sitter-hl-default-patterns.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>